Guide to the Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, Records
Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, Records
1937-2010
1937 2010
Entomological Society of America. Southeastern Branch
MC 00156
The records of the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America (ESA) contain annual meeting programs; photographs of award winners, speakers, and officers; correspondence; financial statements; bound reports; reprints of published Branch history; meeting minutes; hotel contracts; cassette tapes; and a disk. This collection also contains a small file of correspondence and financial information on the Cotton States Branch of the American Association of Economic Entomologists, a predecessor organization. Materials are dated from 1937 to 2010.
The Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America includes members from Alabama, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and the United States Territories of Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands. The organization was established August 2, 1904. A group of entomologists concerned with damage to the cotton crop by the boll weevil elected C. E. Chambliss of South Carolina as Chairman and organized the Association of Official Entomologists of the Cotton Belt, later known as Association of Cotton States Entomologists. The group was active during the ensuing years and was affiliated with the American Association of Economic Entomologists as the Cotton States Branch on December 31, 1925. The American Association of Economic Entomologists merged with the Entomological Society of America in 1953. The name of the branch was changed to Southeastern Branch in 1959.
11 linear feet
North Carolina State University Libraries, Special Collections Research Center
Gift of Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America, September 2009 (Accession no. 2009.0159), and May 2012 (Accession no. 2012.0124)
The collection is organized into four series:
Annual Meeting Programs History Files Chronological Files Photographs
The Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America includes members from Alabama, Arkansas, Florida, Georgia, Louisiana, Mississippi, North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee, and the United States Territories of Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin Islands. The organization was established August 2, 1904. A group of entomologists concerned with damage to the cotton crop by the boll weevil elected C. E. Chambliss of South Carolina as Chairman and organized the Association of Official Entomologists of the Cotton Belt, later known as Association of Cotton States Entomologists. The group was active during the ensuing years and was affiliated with the American Association of Economic Entomologists as the Cotton States Branch on December 31, 1925. The American Association of Economic Entomologists merged with the Entomological Society of America in 1953. The name of the branch was changed to Southeastern Branch in 1959.
The Entomological Society of America is the largest organization in the world serving the professional and scientific needs of entomologists and people in related disciplines. The Entomological Society of America has members affiliated with educational institutions, health agencies, private industry, and government. Members are researchers, teachers, extension service personnel, administrators, marketing representatives, research technicians, consultants, students, and hobbyists. Membership in the Entomological Society of America is open to anyone who has interest or training in insects.
The records of the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America (ESA) contain annual meeting programs; photographs of award winners, speakers, and officers; correspondence; financial statements; bound reports; reprints of published Branch history; meeting minutes; hotel contracts; cassette tapes; and a disk. This collection also contains a small file of correspondence and financial information on the Cotton States Branch of the Amercian Association of Economic Entomologists, a predecessor organization. Materials are dated from 1937 to 2010.
Entomological Society of America. Southeastern Branch; Entomological Society of America. Southeastern Branch; United States Study and teaching Entomology; History United States Entomologists; Research United States Entomology; Entomologists; History United States 20th century Entomology
- Annual Meeting Programs, 1940-2010; 0.75 linear feet
  Materials in this series are arranged in chronological order.
  The Annual Meeting Programs series contains informational programs from the annual meetings of the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America. Materials are dated from 1940 to 2010.
  - Meeting Programs: The Cotton States Branch, American Association of Economic Entomologists and The Cotton States Branch, Entomological Society of America, 1940-1959 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1960-1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1972-1975 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1977-1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1980-1985 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1987-1990 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1993-1997 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 1998-2000 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 2001, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 2003, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 2005, 2006 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 2007, 2008 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Meeting Programs: Entomological Society of America, Southeastern Branch, 2009, 2010 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- History Files, 1941-1989; 0.75 linear feet
  Materials in this series are arranged in chronological order by latest date in file.
  The History Files contain financial summaries and reports, proceedings of meetings, historical records on the Cotton States Branch, branch history reprints, history of entomology departments, meeting agendas and minutes, and other files related to the history of the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America. Materials are dated from 1941 to 1989.
  - Cotton States Branch, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Cotton States Branch, 1955-1958 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - History of Entomological Society of America, 1953-1963 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Southeastern Branch Meeting Proceedings and Financial Summaries, 1953-1965 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Cotton States Branch, 1954, 1968, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Cotton States Branch, 1956-1957, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - History of Entomology Departments, 1961, 1976, undated (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Historical Records, 1959-1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Branch History Reprints (1 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Branch History Reprints (2 of 2), 1979-1980 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Early Financial Information, 1953-1988 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - History of Southeastern Branch, 1941, 1983, 1989 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Chronological Files, 1951-2010; 9 linear feet
  The Chronological Files contain proceedings of meetings, correspondence, committee reports, treasurer’s reports, meeting minutes, material related to committee meetings and to preliminary business meetings, annual meeting plans, hotel contracts, constitution and bylaws, budgets, award plaques and other files related to the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America. Materials are dated from 1951 to 2010.
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Memphis, Tennessee, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Atlanta, Georgia, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence (1 of 2), 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 2), 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Cotton States Branch Seating Chart, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence: Bill Miller, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting: Tampa, Florida, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Cotton State Branch Correspondence, 1956, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1962 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Southeastern Branch, Entomological Society of America: Jackson, Mississippi, 1962-1963 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America: Minutes, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Annual Meeting: Little Rock, Arkansas, 1961, 1965 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meeting: Memphis, Tennessee, 1972-1973 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Committee Meetings, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (1 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (2 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (3 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (4 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (5 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Maxwell, Bowden G. (6 of 6), 1977-1978 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Sparks, Alton N. (1 of 5), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Sparks, Alton N. (2 of 5), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Sparks, Alton N. (3 of 5), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Sparks, Alton N. (4 of 5), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Sparks, Alton N. (5 of 5), 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Turnipseed, Sam G. (1 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Turnipseed, Sam G. (2 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Turnipseed, Sam G. (3 of 3), 1978-1980 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Committee Meetings, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Martin, Dial F. (1 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Martin, Dial F. (2 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Martin, Dial F. (3 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Martin, Dial F. (4 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Martin, Dial F. (5 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Martin, Dial F. (6 of 6), 1978-1981 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Payne, James E. (1 of 3), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Payne, James E. (2 of 3), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Payne, James E. (3 of 3), 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence (1 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (3 of 3), 1980-1982 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Proceeding of Meetings: Atlanta, Georgia, 1981-1982 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Annual Meeting: Greenville, South Carolina, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Call for Papers, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Committee Reports (1 of 4), 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Committee Reports (2 of 4), 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Committee Reports (3 of 4), 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Committee Reports (4 of 4), 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1980-1984 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Financial (1 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Financial (2 of 2), 1982-1984 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Non-members: Entomological Society of America, 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Program (1 of 5), 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Program (2 of 5), 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Program (3 of 5), 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Program (4 of 5), 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Program (5 of 5), 1982-1984 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence (1 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence (3 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Secretary Treasurer (1 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Secretary Treasurer (2 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Secretary Treasurer (3 of 3), 1983-1984 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Committee Reports, 1984 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Musick, G. J. (1 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Musick, G. J. (2 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Musick, G. J. (3 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Musick, G. J. (4 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Musick, G. J. (5 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Musick, G. J. (6 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Musick, G. J. (7 of 7), 1983-1985 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Business Meetings, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Entomological Society of America, 1984-1985 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Appointment of Committees, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Preliminary Business Meetings: Executive Committee (1 of 3), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Preliminary Business Meetings: Executive Committee (2 of 3), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Business Meetings: Executive Committee (3 of 3), 1985 (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Secretary-Treasurer Reports, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Southeastern Branch Correspondence, 1985 (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - General Correspondence (1 of 4), 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 4), 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence (3 of 4), 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (4 of 4), 1985-1987 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1985-1987 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting Plans, 1986-1987 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Committee Guidelines, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1987 (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1986-1988 (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Annual Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Proceedings of Meetings, 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Raleigh, North Carolina (1 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Raleigh, North Carolina (2 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Raleigh, North Carolina (3 of 3), 1987-1988 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Past Programs, 1987-1989 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1988-1989 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meeting Plans, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Nashville, Tennessee (1 of 5), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Nashville, Tennessee (2 of 5), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Nashville, Tennessee (3 of 5), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Nashville, Tennessee (4 of 5), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Proceedings of Meetings: Nashville, Tennessee (5 of 5), 1989 (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1989 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Annual Meeting Plans, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Budget, 1988-1990 (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Award Plaques, 1989-1990 (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Committees, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Treasurer's Report (1 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Treasurer's Report (2 of 2), 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting Plans, 1989-1990 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Industry Contributions, 1990 (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence, 1987-1991 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence (1 of 3), 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - General Correspondence (2 of 3), 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - General Correspondence (3 of 3), 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Hotel Contracts: Orange Beach, Alabama, 1989-1991 (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1989-1991 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Award and Plaques Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Committees, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Meetings, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1990-1991 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Industry Contributions (1 of 2), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Industry Contributions (2 of 2), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (1 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (2 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (3 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (4 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (5 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Pre-registration and Onsite Information: Orange Beach, Alabama (6 of 6), 1991 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Minutes, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Receipts, 1991-1992 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Budget, 1990-1993 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting Plans, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Resolutions of the 67th Annual Meeting, 1992-1993 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Receipts, 1993 (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Preliminary Business Meeting, 1993-1994 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Abbreviated Minutes, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence: J. Eger, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Final Business Meeting, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Final Business Minutes, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - First Mailing, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Member Awards Committee, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Minutes of Preliminary Business Meeting, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 20)
  - Strategic Planning, 1994 (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Second Mailing, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Hotel Contracts (1 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Hotel Contracts (2 of 2), 1993-1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Committee Guidelines (1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Committee Guidelines (2 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: Randy Luttrell (1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence: Randy Luttrell (2 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence to Secretary and Treasurer, 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Receipts (1 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Receipts (2 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Receipts (3 of 3), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Treasurer's Report (1 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Treasurer's Report (2 of 2), 1994-1995 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Auditing Committee, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence: J. Eger, 1995 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Executive Committee Meeting, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Fidelity Bond, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Final Business Meeting, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Insurance Bond, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Internal Revenue Service Form, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - List of Non-members Attending the Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Local Arrangement Committee Report, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Photo Salon Winners, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Preliminary Business Meetings, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Budget, 1991-1996 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Committee Reports, 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Past Programs: Charleston, South Carolina (1 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Past Programs: Charleston, South Carolina (2 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Budget, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Minutes: Asheville, North Carolina, 1996-1997 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2), 1997 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2), 1997 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Cassette Tapes: Final Business Meeting, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    Copies of cassettes must be made prior to patron use.
  - Nominating Committee, Disk, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    Researchers may request copies of digital files. The Special Collections Research Center cannot guarantee that all files will open and will not in all cases have software available to read files
  - Radisson Hotel Contracts, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Annual Meetings (1 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Annual Meetings (2 of 2), 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Awards, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Disk and Registration, 1998 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Industry Contributions, 1999 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1998-2000 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Executive Committee Meeting Minutes and Reports, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Mobile Meeting, 1999-2000 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Hotel Contracts, 1999-2001 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Cassette Tapes: Executive Committee Meeting, 2001 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Little Rock, Arkansas: First Mail Out, 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2001-2002 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Program: Little Rock, Arkansas, 2002 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Meetings, 2001-2003 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Insurance Bond, 1999-2004 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Guidelines for Officers and Committee Chairs, 2004 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Meeting Mail outs (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Meeting Mail outs (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2004 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Tax Exempt Certificates, 1995-2005 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Meetings (1 of 2), 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Meetings (2 of 2), 2003-2005 (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Meeting Reports, 2005 (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence: Hays and Gast, 1999-2006 (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Solicitation of Contributions: Registration Chapter 496, Florida Statutes, 2001-2006 (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Meeting: Wilmington, North Carolina, 2006 (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Minutes and Reports, 2006 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 2006-2007 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Committee Reports and Agendas, 2007 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Meeting: Knoxville, Tennessee, 2007 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Committee Reports and Agendas, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Meeting: Jacksonville, North Carolina, 2008 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Financial Statements, 2001-2009 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - First Mail out, 2009 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - Budget, 2001-2010 (Box 21, Folder 9)
  - Hotel Contracts, 2008-2010 (Box 21, Folder 10)
  - Application for Membership, undated (Box 21, Folder 11)
- Photographs, 1937-1997; 0.5 linear feet
  The Photographs series contains photographs of award winners, speakers, and officers. Materials are dated from 1937 to 1997.
  - Photographs: University of Florida, Florida Entomological Conference, 1937 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Photographs: Annual Banquet, Cotton States Branch, 1954 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - Photographs: Southeastern Branch, Graduate Student Contest Winners, 1970 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - Photographs: Southeastern Branch, Annual Meeting, 1969-1972 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Photographs: Annual Banquet, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, 1975-1977 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - Photographs: Southeastern Branch of the Entomological Society of America Board Members and Contest Winners, 1978 (Box 22, Folder 7)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 8)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, [198?] (Box 22, Folder 9)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, 1979-1980 (Box 22, Folder 10)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, 1980-1983 (Box 22, Folder 11)
  - Photographs: Annual Meeting, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 12)
  - Photographs: Nominees for the J. E. Bussart Memorial Award, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 13)
  - Photographs: Used in Programs, 1988 (Box 22, Folder 14)